**7-Day Europe Historical Itinerary**

**Day 1: Rome**
- Morning: Visit the Colosseum and Roman Forum.
- Afternoon: Explore Palatine Hill and Piazza Navona.
- Evening: Enjoy traditional Italian cuisine at a local trattoria.

**Day 2: Rome**
- Morning: Visit the Vatican City, including the Sistine Chapel and Vatican Museums.
- Afternoon: Explore the Spanish Steps and Trevi Fountain.
- Evening: Relax at a local café.

**Day 3: Paris**
- Morning: Take the Eurostar to Paris.
- Afternoon: Visit the Eiffel Tower and the Louvre Museum.
- Evening: Stroll along the Seine and enjoy a French dinner.

**Day 4: Paris**
- Morning: Explore Montmartre and visit Sacré-Cœur Basilica.
- Afternoon: Visit Notre-Dame Cathedral (exterior).
- Evening: Enjoy a wine-tasting session at a local vineyard.

**Day 5: London**
- Morning: Take the Eurostar to London.
- Afternoon: Visit Buckingham Palace and the Tower of London.
- Evening: Explore Camden Market for unique shopping and dining experiences.

**Day 6: London**
- Morning: Visit the British Museum.
- Afternoon: Stroll through Hyde Park.
- Evening: Attend a West End theatre show.

**Day 7: Amsterdam**
- Morning: Travel from London to Amsterdam by train.
- Afternoon: Visit the Anne Frank House and Rijksmuseum.
- Evening: Take a canal cruise and enjoy Dutch cuisine.

**Transportation:**
- Use the Eurostar for travel between London and Paris.
- Take trains from Paris to Amsterdam.
- Utilize local public transport within each city.

**Budget Guidelines:**
- Allocate approximately $300 per day for activities, food, and local transport.
- Consider booking train tickets and attraction entrances in advance for better rates.

**Additional Tips:**
- Check visiting hours and book tickets for popular sites beforehand.
- Research safety tips for each city and ensure all travel documents are in order.
- Enjoy the local cuisine by dining at cafes and trying street food to stay within budget.

This itinerary balances historical exploration with cultural experiences, ensuring a memorable and enriching trip through four key European cities.